# SHAULI RAVFOGEL

(+972) 0549508315  $\diamond$ shauli.ravfogel@gmail.com  $\diamond$ shauli-ravfogel.netlify.app

Third-year Ph.D student at BIU NLP lab, supervised by Prof. Youv Goldberg. My research interests encompass representation learning, unsupervised machine learning, causal attribution, and interpretability of neural models for NLP.

#### **EDUCATION**

Ph.D in Natural Language Processing and Machine Learning

2020 - Present

Bar-Ilan University

Advisor: Prof. Yoav Goldberg

Research Topics: Controlled Representation Learning; Bias Mitigation; Interpretability; Causality

M.Sc in Natural Language Processing and Machine Learning

2018 - 2020

Bar-Ilan University

Advisor: Prof. Yoav Goldberg

Research Topics: Syntax Acquisition in Neural Networks; Typological Diversity

**B.Sc** in Computer Science

2015 - 2018

Bar-Ilan University

Graduated with a final grade of 90.

Final Project: Implicit Syntax Learning in Morphologically-Rich Languages.

**B.Sc** in Chemistry

2010 - 2013

Bar-Ilan University

Graduated with a final grade of 90; Dean's Honors in 2011.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## Machine Learning Lecturer

Oct 2021 - March 2021

Teaching an introduction to machine learning course for brain science students.

## Ph.D. Research Intern, AI2 Israel

Jan 2020 - Present

Working as a research intern on a project which focuses on combining symbolic and neural-based IE.

## Machine Learning Teaching Assistant

May 2019 - 2021

TA in a graduate-level machine learning course for brain science students.

## **Medicinal Chemist**

Sep 2013 - Sep 2016

Research position focused on civilian defense and protection against chemical and biological threats.

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

- Royi Rassin\*, Shauli Ravfogel\*, Yoav Goldberg. DALLE-2 is Seeing Double: Flaws in Word-to-Entity Mapping. BlackBoxNLP@EMNLP 2022.
- Shauli Ravfogel, Francisco Vargas, Yoav Goldberg and Ryan Cotterell. Adversarial Concept Erasure in Kernel Space. EMNLP 2022.
- Hila Gonen, Shauli Ravfogel, and Yoav Goldberg. Analyzing Gender Representation in Multilingual Models. Proceedings of the 7th Workshop on Representation Learning for NLP 2022 (Best Paper Award).

- Shauli Ravfogel, Michael Twiton, Yoav Goldberg and Ryan Cotterell. Linear Adversarial Concept Erasure. International Conference on Machine Learning. PMLR, 2022.
- Elad Ben-Zaken, Shauli Ravfogel, and Yoav Goldberg. Bitfit: Simple parameter-efficient fine-tuning for transformer-based masked language-models. ACL 2022.
- Shauli Ravfogel\*, Grusha Prasad\*, Tal Linzen and Yoav Goldberg. Counterfactual Interventions Reveal the Causal Effect of Relative Clause Representations on Agreement Prediction. CoNLL 2021.
- Alon Jacovi, Swabha Swayamdipta, **Shauli Ravfogel**, Yanai Elazar, Yejin Choi, Yoav Goldberg, **Contrastive Explanations for Model Interpretability**. EMNLP 2021.
- Shauli Ravfogel, Hillel Taub-Tabib, Yoav Goldberg. Neural Extractive Search. ACL 2021 demo track.
- Shauli Ravfogel, Yanai Elazar, Jacob Goldberger and Yoav Goldberg. Unsupervised Distillation of Syntactic Information from Contextualized Word Representations. Black-BoxNLP@EMNLP 2020.
- Carlo Meloni\*, **Shauli Ravfogel**\*, and Yoav Goldberg. **Ab Antiquo: Neural Proto-language Reconstruction**. NAACL 2021.
- Yanai Elazar, Shauli Ravfogel, Alon Jacovi and Yoav Goldberg. Amnesic Probing: Behavioral Explanation with Amnesic Counterfactuals. Accepted in TACL 2021.
- Hila Gonen, Shauli Ravfogel, Yanai Elazar and Yoav Goldberg. It's not Greek to mBERT: Inducing Word-Level Translations from Multilingual BERT. BlackBoxNLP 2020.
- Shauli Ravfogel, Yanai Elazar, Hila Gonen, Micheal Twiton and Yoav Goldberg. Null It Out: Guarding Protected Attributes by Iterative Nullspace Projection. ACL 2020.
- Shauli Ravfogel, Yoav Goldberg and Tal Linzen. Studying the Inductive Biases of RNNs with Synthetic Variations of Natural Languages. NAACL-HLT 2019.
- Shauli Ravfogel, Francis M. Tyers and Yoav Goldberg. Can LSTM Learn to Capture Agreement? The Case of Basque. BlackboxNLP@EMNLP 2018.

## INVITED TALKS

- October 2021, the SIGTYP lecture series. Linear Controlled Representation Learning.
- December 2020, prof. Roi Reichart's Research Group, Technion. Assessing the Causal Effect of Linguistic Concepts with Counterfactual Representations.
- March 2020, Yale Linguistics Department. Unsupervised Distillation of Syntactic Information from Neural Representations.
- February 2020, Johns Hopkins Computation and Psycholinguistics Lab. Neutralizing Concepts in the Representations of Neural Models.
- February 2019, ONLP lab, the Open University of Israel. Implicit Syntax Acquisition by NNs in Morphologically Rich Languages.

## ACADEMIC SERVICE

Reviewer: ACL 2020, CoNLL 2020, HAMLETS@NeurIPS2020, NAACL 2021, ACL-IJCNLP 2021, EMNLP 2021, ARR 2021-2022, ICML 2022

## **AWARDS**

- 2022-2023: Bloomberg Data Science PhD Fellowship.
- 2022: Israeli Council for Higher Education (Vatat) Fellowship for outstanding PhD Students in Data Science (declined).
- 2022: Best paper award, RepL4NLP workshop.
- 2021-2024: The Presidential Scholarship for Outstanding PhD Students.
- 2020-2021: The Departmental Scholarship for Outstanding Doctoral Fellows.
- 2011: Dean's Honors (Chemistry)